# **Paul Smith**

55 Central Avenue, Dogsthorpe, Peterborough, Cambridgeshire. PE1 4LW.

#### TEL.07523756851

# paul.smith@theforkbeard.com

## **OBJECTIVE**

Bringing over Thirty years of experience in the amenity horticulture and commercial soft landscaping industry, project managing multiple sites; I want to use the skills and work ethic developed to add to the new skills that I am learning while training as a software developer. I am excited by the challenges this direction of career change is offering and am enjoying the new opportunities to exercise my solution finding skills in this environment.

#### **SKILLS & ABILITIES**

While I have thoroughly enjoyed the physical contact with the land my college training and supervisory positions has encouraged me to continue to exercise the administrative side of my industry.

Interpreting site drawings for:-

- Tendering/quotations,
- Planning works,
- Ordering materials, plant and manpower
- Executing said plans.

Using Exel, Word and Email for:-

- All above plus,
- Creating risk assessments, Method Statements and safe systems of work.
- To gather evidence of production for invoicing.
- To resolve complaint issues to customer satisfaction

This was made infinitely easier a decade ago with the increase in availability of smart phones.

I am currently studying for a diploma in full stack web development at CODE institute and have already started a portfolio of websites.

# **Experience**

Code Institute, Studying Diploma in software development, 02/02/2020 – Present.

After getting feedback from a few interviews, I enrolled here to improve my office-based skills.

Freelance Site management operative 19/09/2018 – 09/07/2019

Self employed in providing regular site maintenance to commercial properties and a stately home.

I was forced by long term injuries to cease the physical activities and seek more office-based roles.

Landscape Team Leader, Warwick Taylor Landscapes 10/10/2016-19/09/2018

The key responsibility was to project manage the soft landscaping of multiple sites. As such I was site supervisor for my company on many sites including The Ely cinema complex and the Wicks retail park at Ipswich. The company ceased trading 09/2018.

Landscape Team Leader, County Grounds Maintenance 16/03/2013-10/10/2016

The key responsibility was to project manage the soft landscaping of multiple sites. As such I was site supervisor for my company on many sites including The Kings Lynn Innovation Centre and many school refurbishments projects. I Was head hunted for Warwick Taylor Landscapes.

#### **EDUCATION**

National Certificate in Horticulture, Wisbech, Cambs. College of agriculture and horticulture. 1989-1990

NVQ level 2 in Groundsmanship and Sports Turf Management, Melton Mowbray, Brooksby 1992-1993

## **LEADERSHIP**

Whilst my problem solving abilities probably led to my gravitating into supervision roles they were tested and pushed to the limits by the inclusion of needing to encourage the best out of others. For over 2 decades I have with varying success worked as team leader or supervisor. I am lucky to be able to remember multiple sites drawings at once and be able to guide teammates through problems over the phone.

#### **COMMUNICATION**

A nice Segway to communication skills I have developed as a result of by interactions with colleagues and customers. Which if there is still the question of describing a person's weakness in today's interview fashion, communication was one I could claim in my early career. This led to my listening more and developing interest in people I was interacting with. I still believe that I have a lot to learn with my communication skills which is one of the reasons I feel office work would benefit my personal development.